Guide to the James G. Harbord Papers 1902-1949 MS 1493
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: General correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence A-Z
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January 1932 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", November-December 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", July-October 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", June 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", April-May 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", March 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-March 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", October-December 1930 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 1)
      Includes propaganda on Communism/Combatting communists; Harbord's introduction for the broadcast series, "When Mr. Baker Made War;" biographical material; copy of the American Legion Monthly.
    - Correspondence "Publicity", July-September 1930 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", April-June 1930 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-March 1930 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", October-December 1929 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", May-September 1929 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", April 1929 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-March 1929 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", July-December 1928 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", May-June 1928 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-April 1928 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", July-December 1927 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", April-June 1927 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-March 1927 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", July-December 1926 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", June 1926 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", March-May 1926 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-February 1926 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", October-December 1925 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", June-September 1925 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-May 1925 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", September-December 1924 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", June-August 1924 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", February-May 1924 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January 1924 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", September-December 1923 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", June-August 1923 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", March-May 1923 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "Publicity", January-February 1923 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Q", 1931-1944 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Philippines President Manuel Quezon and his wife Aurora discussing their health and the prospects for Philippine independence and U.S./Philippines relations. Also includes letters regarding the health of Mrs. Harbord, and a letter of recommendation dated April 9, 1935 for John P. Quander, "an extremely intelligent, well-educated colored man, one of the best stenographers I have ever known, and thoroughly competent for a position such as that you mention in your letter."
    - Correspondence "Q", 1923-1930 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Philippines President Manuel Quezon discussing social and racial attitudes toward Filipinos ["natives"].
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1944-1948 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 5)
      Notable correspondents include General Charles Dudley Rhodes (includes biographical sketch). Interesting letterheads include the Inn at Rancho Santa Fe and Forest Hills Inn, Long Island. Topics include travel arrangements to San Francisco.
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1941-1943 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 6)
      Includes letter to Celia Reber discussing difficulty of getting servants and a report on the Conference on Public Relations sponsored by National Association of Manufacturers.
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1938-1940 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 7)
      Includes pamphlet titled "Memorandum of the meetings in Washington of the Selective Service Advertising Group and the War Department," a letter from Senator Reynolds regarding anti-immigration legislation, and a letter discussing Philippine independence. In addition, there is a letter from Harbord dated December 16, 1938 announcing his re-marriage.
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 8)
      Includes pamphlets on "The Crisis and the Political Parties," "A Primer of Capitalism Illustrated," and "American Liberty League." Also includes sympathy letters regarding the death of Mrs. Harbord.
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence regarding the Hoover campaign.
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 11)
      Includes letter dated December 9, 1930 declining request for help with employment: "We are laying off employees by the hundreds and reducing the compensation of many of those who stay."
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 13)
      Includes pamphlet on the "International Institute of China Inc. or the Mission Among the Higher Classes in China" and a copy of the International Journal (in Chinese)
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1924 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "RA-RH", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 15)
      Includes letter regarding campaign to have Harbord nominated as Vice-President [to Coolidge; Dawes nominated instead] and a letter discussing the Ku Klux Klan. Also includes pamphlet on "Principles of Evacuation."
    - Correspondence "Retired Pay", 1933, 1945 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1942 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1941 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1940 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1930 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1928-1929 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "RI-RY", 1923-1925 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 13)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 1)
      This note pertains to all Republican Campaign Correspondence. Includes letters and documents relating to Harbord's work with the Union league, such as his invitations to Paramount Pictures executives to participate in the Hoover Campaign; a comprehensive campaign pamphlet for Hoover; a national "Who's Who" poll for Hoover; "Hoovergrams" for mailing in contributions to his campaign, and two photos of him inundated by them; and a copy of the Kourier Magazine by the Ku Klux Klan, noted with thanks by Harbord.
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 2)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 3)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 4)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 5)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 6)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 7)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 8)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 9)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 10)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 11)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 12)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 13)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 14)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 15)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 16)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 17)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 18)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 19)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 20)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 21)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 47, Folder 22)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 1)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 2)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 3)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 4)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 5)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 6)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 7)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 8)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 9)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 10)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 11)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 12)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 13)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 14)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 15)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 16)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 17)
    - Republican Campaign Correspondence (Offsite-box 48, Folder 18)
    - Republican Campaign Posters: Hoover and Curtis, circa 1929 (Box OS medium, Folder Harbord OS1)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1923-1926 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 1)
      This note pertains to all "SA-SC" folders. Interesting ephemera includes business cards and a marching songs book called "Freedom's Drums." Letters discuss Mrs. Harbord's health (her bout of typhoid fever), radio sets, the cadets at West Point, trips to South America, Europe, Cuba and Mexico; automobiles; the San Antonio lodge; Margaret Deland's writing (including "Old Chester Tales," "The Iron Woman," and a "little book" that is "beautifully written and bears upon the question of the Negro in America in an interesting way"), "oriental matters" in the Philippines, rapid growth in population and industry of California and the Pacific Coast states, the Hoover Campaign, the Crow Indian Agency, Custer Battlefield, "Anti-Hoover people," real estate, the fall of Paris "to the beasts of Europe," the American Legion, servants, WWII, the Philadelphia Women's Forum on Post-War Planning, and railroad lines. There are also pamphlets on "Labor-Credit: A Property Owner's Solution of the Unemployment Problem," "Coordination of Rail and Highway Transportation," "The Present Economic State of Germany," "Plan of the Committee in Aid of the Depositors of the Bank of United States," and "The Bank of United States Report on Financial Condition."
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1934-1937 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1938-1941 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1941-1944 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "SA-SC", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 8)
      This note pertains to all "SE-SO" folders. Letters discuss General Motors Strike; books and newspaper articles; Eisenhower; foreign policies of the New Deal government; President Roosevelt; life insurance; Civil Penalties Bill; anti-trust laws; Consumers' Goods Industries Committee; WWII; Eastman Kodak Co.; the Equal Rights Amendment; estate planning; television; the Securities Act; regional plan proposals for the improvement of Westchester County; West Point; and golf. Also includes pamphlets on "International 'New Dealism,'" "An Appraisal of the Public Utility Act of 1935, and "Problems under the Security Exchange Act."
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1941-1944 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1937-1941 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1934-1936 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1930 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1927-1929 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1926 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1925 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "SE-SO", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1941-1946 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1935-1938 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "SP-SY", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1943-1947 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1940-1942 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1934-1936 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "T-U", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1944 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1943 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1942 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1941 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1936-1938 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1933 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "V-WA", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1943-1945 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "WE-WH", 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1942-1944 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1938-1939 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1937 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1936 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1935 (Offsite-box 52, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1925 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1924 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1923 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "WI-WY" + "X, Y, Z", 1922 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 9)
    - Pacific/Asia trip contacts?, 1938 (Offsite-box 55)
      This is a set of index cards, invitations, and calling cards that appears to be contacts or potential contacts for Harbord during a 1938 trip to Hawaii, Australia, China, Japan, and perhaps elsewhere in the Pacific.
    - Index cards: Correspondence index; Addresses, 1910s-1940s (Offsite-box 56)
      Scope and Contents
      This box holds the rehoused contents from Harbord's original 4 drawer wooden filing cabinet. Three drawers included index cards with what appears to be an index to his correspondence. The bulk of these cards refer to correspondence from the 1920s, but some date back into the 1910s and some go to the 1930s and 1940s. The fourth drawer, labeled "Addresses," included index cards, calling cards, paper slips, and similar forms with names and contact information, arranged alphabetically. Most is undated.
  - Subseries I.2: Individual and important correspondents
    This subseries contains Harbord's correspondence with Charles Dawes (Brigadier General who served as chairman of the purchasing board for the American Expeditionary Forces), General Pershing, Dwight Morrow (lawyer and banker with J.P. Morgan), and Theodore Roosevelt. There are also two folders of letters from various other significant correspondents.
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 11)
      This note pertains to all folders of Dawes correspondence. Letters discuss concerns about promoting General Marshall, post-war economy of Great Britain, servants and servant problems, atomic bomb and policy toward Japan, tensions between the U.K. and East during the war, Churchill, and the Monroe Doctrine and reluctance to enter WWII.
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1945 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1944 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1943 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1942 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1941 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1940 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1935-1938 (Offsite-box 53, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1929 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1929 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1921-1924 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Charles Dawes, 1921-1944 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1941-1947 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 8)
      This note pertains to all folder of Pershing Correspondence.
      Letters discuss Harbord's disappointment about how the radio channels covered the war, and career advice from Pershing (Pershing suggests Harbord take a job in the Philippines, and heavily dissuades him from taking the mayorship of NYC, given that he already has all the important commercial and political connections from RCA post)/ Also include Harbord's draft of a eulogy for Pershing, whose death was in 1948. In it, he mentions the tragic fire at el Presidio, Pershing's earlier home: "I was at the Presidio of San Francisco during the tragedy which in 1915 robbed [Pershing] of his young wife and three little girls."
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1936-1939 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1930-1932 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1925-1929 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with General Pershing, 1918-1924 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 14)
    - Morrow Correspondence, 1926-1930 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 15)
    - Morrow Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 16)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Correspondence, 1917-1919 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 17)
      Includes ten letters from Theodore Roosevelt to Harbord, and one letter from Roosevelt's son Archibald, along with Harbord's responses. Letters discuss Roosevelt's request to raise a division in WWI (ultimately denied by President Wilson), for which he was recruiting Harbord; the death of Roosevelt's son Quentin in service as a pilot; and the military service of Roosevelt's other sons.
      Note that only photocopies of the Roosevelt letters are available to researchers.
    - Theodore Roosevelt letters (originals) -- RESTRICTED, 1917-1919 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 17A)
    - Misc. Important Letters (Offsite-box 54, Folder 18)
      Correspondents include William Taft, Marshal Petain, and others
    - Misc. Important Letters (Offsite-box 54, Folder 19)
      Correspondents include Herbert Hoover, Eilhu Root, Marshal Petain, and others
- Series II: Military papers
  This series includes cablegrams and reports from World War I, as well as articles and reports on both civilian and military aspects of the Philippines from Harbord's years of service there.
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence, reports and diary
    This subseries contains cablegrams, war reports, and papers relating to the 1937 Convention of the American Legion. There is also one folder of military photographs and a folder of pamphlets.
    Cablegrams
    Cablegrams A 813-A 2099 (boxes II.1-2) are cablegrams received by Harbord which primarily relate to personnel concerns. Earlier cablegrams mostly center around logistics (shipments, production, training, payments, replies to queries) while later cablegrams are mostly concerned with discharge, messages to soldiers, and verification of soldier status (location, health, condition, rank, citizenship).
    These cables are organized topically by individual date and labeled with alphanumerical code, typically ranging 1-2 pages in length per topic group. Each cable is subgrouped into numbered paragraphs which represent separate messages.